A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Politics - New York City Office, Series J.1 FA345
Rockefeller Archive Center
- New York State Gubernatorial Campaigns, 1958-1970; 3; 33 Document Box(es)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Committee for a Republican Victory (Box 41, Folder 420)
    General correspondence; 'When a Rockefeller Needs a Friend' "National Review," August 2, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Contributions (Box 42, Folder 421)
    NAR letters of appreciation for contributions to his campaign fund.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Contributions (Box 42, Folder 422)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Contributions (Box 42, Folder 423)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Contributions (Box 42, Folder 424)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Contributions, William A. Burden Letters (Box 42, Folder 425)
    Letters of appreciation for contributions by NAR campaign staff. Winthrop Rockefeller's contribution to campaign.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Acceptance Speech, August 25, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 426)
    New York Republican State Convention, Rochester
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Arrangements (Box 42, Folder 427)
    New York Republican State Convention, Rochester. Room assignments, travel plans, and scheduled events for the convention.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Clippings (Box 42, Folder 428)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Correspondence (Box 43, Folder 429)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Delegates (Box 43, Folder 430)
    New York Republican State Convention, Rochester. Lists of delegates for each county to the convention.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Platform (Box 43, Folder 431)
    New York Republican State Convention, Rochester. Correspondence and memoranda concerning the drafting of the party's position on issues for New York State.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Pre-convention Plans (Box 43, Folder 432)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Rochester Headquarters (Box 43, Folder 433)
    New York Republican State Convention, Rochester. Memoranda recommending the establishment of a headquarters nearby the convention site and the hotel for staff to work.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - Speeches (Box 43, Folder 434)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Convention - TV and Radio (Box 43, Folder 435)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - "County Contest Plan" - Letters to Chairmen (Box 43, Folder 436)
    NAR response to county officials concerning his favoritism of Judson Morhouse's "Contest Plan." NAR letters to county chairmen.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - "County Contest Plan" - Letters to Vice Chairmen (Box 43, Folder 437)
    NAR response to county officials concerning his favoritism of Judson Morhouse's "Contest Plan." NAR letters to county vice chairmen.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Announcement Replies (Box 43, Folder 438)
    Letters from democrats in response to the announcement of the Democrats for Rockefeller organization.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Contributions (Box 44, Folder 439)
    Letters of thanks.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Contributions (Box 44, Folder 440)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Contributions (Box 44, Folder 441)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - General (Box 44, Folder 442)
    Memoranda and correspondence of the organization.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - NAR Letters of Appreciation (Box 44, Folder 443)
    Letters to supporters and staff.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - NAR Statement (Box 44, Folder 444)
    Statement of support for the organization made by NAR.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Publicity (Box 44, Folder 445)
    Press releases and public appearances by NAR.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Democrats for Rockefeller - Volunteers (Box 44, Folder 446)
    Letters of thanks from NAR to campaign workers.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Drivers (Box 44, Folder 447)
    Handwritten notes August 14, 1958; names of unions & men affiliated with them, individuals to be used in campaign driving.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Groups & Clubs (Box 44, Folder 448)
    Mission to Israel by B. Katzen, special consultant to Secretary of State; address January 23, 1958 at America-Israel Society dinner; groups supporting Rockefeller.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Hinman, George L. (Box 44, Folder 449)
    Miscellaneous correspondence; memos re NAR's campaign.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Invitations and Appeals (Box 44, Folder 450)
    Miscellaneous invitations to NAR to attend dinners, conventions, etc. & NAR replies.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Invitations to Speak (Box 45, Folder 451)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Civil Rights (Box 45, Folder 452)
    Equality of opportunity speech outline September 12, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Crime (Box 45, Folder 453)
    Law enforcement speech outline September 13, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Democratic Party (Box 45, Folder 454)
    Various attacks on Democratic incompetence; "Harriman's Flip-Flops," his inability to stick to original position on issues; Crime Commission Testimony, 1958 - Carmine Desapio.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - "Economic Drift" (Box 45, Folder 455)
    Ogdensburg background material; suggested outline for NY Young Republican Club speech August 11, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - "Empire State Plan" (Box 45, Folder 456)
    People involved in The Empire State Plan, November 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Labor (Box 45, Folder 457)
    Remarks by Senate Majority Leader Walter J. Mahoney, October 22, 1957; Luncheon with Labor groups, September 22, 1958; NAR policy statement October 3, 1958; John Davison Rockefeller, Jr. on labor unions.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - New York State Finances (Box 45, Folder 458)
    State finances & departments; New York State budget process; state finances September 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Philanthropies (Box 45, Folder 459)
    NAR & Italian-American Relations; Irish recipients of Fellowship Awards, Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller & Jewish causes; contributions to Jewish & Negro philanthropies; statement of Negroes denouncing attacks on NAR record (& family record) in field of interracial relations; notes on Rockefeller family contributions to better racial understanding.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Issues - Proposed Programs (Box 45, Folder 460)
    Summaries of programs proposed by NAR on all chief issues; miscellaneous memos by Ronan and Jamieson; position on state legislature to prevent discrimination in housing.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Itineraries (Box 45, Folder 461)
    NAR itinerary July 1958 - November 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Itineraries (Box 45, Folder 462)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Itineraries (Box 46, Folder 463)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Itineraries (Box 46, Folder 464)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Legal (Box 46, Folder 465)
    Memos; campaign expenses, September 1958; political contributions & contributors.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters to Chairs and Vice Chairs, October 24, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 466)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters to Citizens, October 28, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 467)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters to Congressional Candidates, October 22, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 468)
    Letter from NAR to all Congressional candidates re victory for the Republican Party.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters to "Rural Citizens for Rockefeller", October 28, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 469)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters of Appreciation (Box 46, Folder 470)
    NAR letters of appreciation & thanks to independent committees; for use of stores; appreciation for contributions & support during campaign by county chairman & vice chairman; appreciation for letters of support from public; NAR letter to rural citizens in appreciation for support by Rural Citizens for Rockefeller-Keating.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters of Appreciation (Box 46, Folder 471)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters of Support (Box 47, Folder 472)
    Correspondence from citizens supporting NAR, some NAR replies.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters of Support (Box 47, Folder 473)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Letters of Support (Box 47, Folder 474)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Lowe, Richard A. (Box 47, Folder 475)
    Miscellaneous correspondence; National Negro Independent Civic & Political Association, Inc.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Lubell, Samuel (Box 47, Folder 476)
    Correspondence re Lubell's trips around the country & surveys; The Puerto Rican Migration; How Farmers Feel.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Lubell, Samuel, Survey Report, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 477)
    Survey on the balance of voting, GOP candidates, Rockefeller as a candidate, the issues, farmers' attitudes, attitudes about integration, Negro & Puerto Rican migration.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Lubell, Samuel, Survey Report, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 478)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Mahoney, Walter (Box 47, Folder 479)
    Miscellaneous correspondence with the NYS State Senator; highlights of the 1957-1958 legislative enactments affecting labor.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Memoranda & Telephone Calls (Box 48, Folder 480)
    Telephone calls; trips; Rockefeller Harlem Walking Tour October 8, 1958; miscellaneous dinners & appointments.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Memoranda - General (Box 48, Folder 481)
    Business survey map; miscellaneous memos; statement by NAR June 30, 1958; pre-convention memos & notices of press conferences; telephone calls; telegrams.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Memoranda - General (Box 48, Folder 482)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Metropolitan Political Club (Box 48, Folder 483)
    NAR correspondence with with MPC, Charles B. Schmertz, Morton Lawrence of NY Telephone; Rockefeller for Governor Club opening July 21, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Morhouse, L. Judson (Box 48, Folder 484)
    Miscellaneous memos re 1958 campaign; memoranda of telephone conversations with Morhouse.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - News Summaries, 1956-1958 (Box 48, Folder 485)
    Summaries of articles on gubernatorial campaign in Manhattan & out of town newspapers, August 1956 - September 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - News Summaries, 1956-1958 (Box 48, Folder 486)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees, Organs, Chairs (Box 49, Folder 487)
    List of each county organization and its respective chairs.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Albany (Box 49, Folder 488)
    NAR's involvement in the named county with respect to the election.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Allegheny (Box 49, Folder 489)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Bronx (Box 49, Folder 490)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Broome (Box 49, Folder 491)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Cattaraugus (Box 49, Folder 492)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Cayuga (Box 49, Folder 493)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Chautauqua (Box 49, Folder 0493A)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Chemung (Box 49, Folder 494)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Chenango (Box 49, Folder 495)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Clinton (Box 49, Folder 496)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Columbia (Box 49, Folder 497)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Cortland (Box 49, Folder 498)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Delaware (Box 49, Folder 499)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Dutchess (Box 49, Folder 500)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Erie (Box 49, Folder 501)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Essex (Box 49, Folder 502)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Franklin (Box 49, Folder 503)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Fulton (Box 49, Folder 504)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Genessee (Box 49, Folder 505)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Greene (Box 49, Folder 506)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Hamilton (Box 49, Folder 507)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Herkimer (Box 49, Folder 508)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Jefferson (Box 49, Folder 509)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Kings (Box 49, Folder 510)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Lewis (Box 49, Folder 511)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Livingston (Box 49, Folder 512)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Madison (Box 49, Folder 513)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Monroe (Box 49, Folder 514)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Montgomery (Box 49, Folder 515)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Nassau (Box 49, Folder 516)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - New York (Box 49, Folder 517)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Niagara (Box 49, Folder 518)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Oneida (Box 49, Folder 519)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Onondaga (Box 49, Folder 520)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Ontario (Box 49, Folder 521)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Orange (Box 49, Folder 522)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Orleans (Box 49, Folder 523)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Oswego (Box 49, Folder 524)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Otsego (Box 49, Folder 525)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Putnam (Box 50, Folder 526)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Queens (Box 50, Folder 527)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Rensselaer (Box 50, Folder 528)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Richmond (Box 50, Folder 529)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Rockland (Box 50, Folder 530)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - St. Lawrence (Box 50, Folder 531)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Saratoga (Box 50, Folder 532)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Schenectady (Box 50, Folder 533)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Schoharie (Box 50, Folder 534)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Schuyler (Box 50, Folder 0534A)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Seneca (Box 50, Folder 535)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Steuben (Box 50, Folder 536)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Suffolk (Box 50, Folder 537)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Sullivan (Box 50, Folder 538)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Tioga (Box 50, Folder 539)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Tompkins (Box 50, Folder 540)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Ulster (Box 50, Folder 541)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Warren (Box 50, Folder 542)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Washington (Box 50, Folder 543)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Wayne (Box 50, Folder 544)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Wyoming (Box 50, Folder 545)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - New York State County Republican Committees - Yates (Box 50, Folder 546)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Offers of Assistance (Box 50, Folder 547)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Offers of Assistance (Box 50, Folder 548)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Offers of Assistance (Box 50, Folder 549)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Office (Box 51, Folder 550)
    Staff of NAR for Governor headquarters, room 242, 19 West 50th Street; bills, office management, campaign expenses.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Office Inventory (Box 51, Folder 551)
    Additions to Rockefeller for Governor office inventory; August 4, 1958, office inventories, July 1958. Miscellaneous bills, furniture rentals.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Office Mailings, 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 552)
    Postal zone directory, 1956; August 11, 1958 mailing to delegates & alternates; campaign literature mailing.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Organization Charts (Box 51, Folder 553)
    Framework of state staff.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Perkins, Roswell B. (Box 51, Folder 554)
    Summary of Plans Committee meeting September 5, 1958; miscellaneous memos re: campaign, meetings, names of individuals in People-for-Rockefeller organization, Young Republican speech requests.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Photographs (Box 51, Folder 555)
    Requests for autographed photos.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Photographs (Box 51, Folder 556)
    NAR campaign photographs: Rochester, NY at Republican Convention; at Decca Record Plant, September 11, 1958; Carnegie Hall, August 20, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Planning Meetings (Box 51, Folder 557)
    Memos concerning meetings to be held July and August 1958; Strategy Meetings & Board, agendas 7/21/58-8/13/58.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Political Leaders Lists (Box 51, Folder 558)
    Brief biographical sketches on the Republican leadership of New York State.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Political Summaries (Box 51, Folder 559)
    Reports culled from New York State newspapers on political events in New York State.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Post Election Letters (Box 51, Folder 560)
    Correspondence to NAR on victory; NAR letters to victorious Republicans.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Progress Report - R. Perkins (Box 51, Folder 561)
    Progress reports re delegates, convention arrangements, media, research, financial & legal aspects, groups & clubs, campaign organization & schedule.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Bills (Box 51, Folder 562)
    Reporters, 1958 Republican Convention; publicity materials - buttons, printed material, etc.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 563)
    Public suggestions re aiding Rockefeller campaign; requests for material; memos re newspaper & interviews; copies of telegrams sent; NAR position cards; Francis A. Jamieson correspondence with John Bett re NAR's text for "Battle Page" in "New York Post," 10/24/58-10/31/58; misc. memos re radio, TV & newspaper programs & interviews.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 564)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 565)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 566)
    Clippings, press releases on campaign activities.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Releases and articles (Box 52, Folder 567)
    Official press releases and statements.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Publicity - Releases and articles, "New York Age" (Box 52, Folder 568)
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Puerto Rican Rally (Box 52, Folder 569)
    Points in statement; rally October 24, 1958; Rockefeller Fiesta, October 23, 1958.
  - 1958 Gubernatorial Campaign - Subject Files - Questions and Answers (Box 52, Folder 570)